# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello everyone, this is Wang Gang
# 本期视频我和大家分享
In this video I'll share with you...
# 处理猪肚的小技巧
Techniques for processing pork tripe
# 首先我们准备新鲜的猪肚一个（约750克）
First of all, prepare a fresh tripe (about 750g)
# 市场上售卖的猪肚一般都是被摊主翻过来的
Pork tripe bought from the market is often turned inside out
# 这样看起来更有卖相，同样肥肠也是如此
It presents better that way, the same for pork intestine
# 下一步开始处理
Next step, process the tripe
# 首先我们用剪刀将猪肚剪开
First, cut the tripe open with scissors
# 这样更方便内外清洗和处理
This makes it easier to clean both the interior and exterior of the tripe
# 猪肚剪开之后再去除猪肚里面多余的油脂
Remove the excessive fat content inside the tripe
# 这层油脂跟肥肠的不同它有一定的腥味
Different from port intestine, this layer of fat has a smelly odor
# 去除得约干净越好
So try your best eliminating it
# 手撕不动的同学也可以用剪刀剪掉
If you cannot tear it off, try scissors
# 肥油去除之后加入热水挼（搓）洗几遍
When done, rub the tripe thoroughly with hot water
# 这一步的目的是去除猪肚表层的胃液
Rubbing would wash off any unwanted gastric juice on the surface of the tribe
# 同学们注意这一步必须用热水挼 （抓）
Make sure that you rub with hot water...
# 否则剩余的肥油容易腻手
Or the fat residual might stick to your hand
# 同时对胃酸过敏的同学可以戴手套操作
People allergic to gastric acid may use gloves
# 以免对手造成腐蚀
It also protects your hands from the acid
# 下一步开始深度清理
Next, deep cleaning to the tripe
# 首先在盆中加入一把食用盐挼（抓）洗3分钟
Add a grain of salt, then rub it for 3 minutes
# 这一步是对猪肚的初步处理
This gives the tripe a primary processing
# 3分钟之后加入滚水清洗干净
After 3 minutes, pour in boiling water to rinse it off
# 清洗干净之后再次加入一大把食用盐
Add a generous handful of salt after draining the water
# 加入适量的高度白酒用力抓5分钟
Add some strong liquor to rub the tripe hard for another 5 minutes
# 这一步的目的是去除腥臭味
This should eliminate all the odor
# 中途再加入一小把干淀粉挼
Add a grain of starch and continue rubbing the tripe
# 加干淀粉的目的是带走抓出来的黏液
Starch helps to remove the slime as an unwanted product from the preparation process
# 温馨提示：同学们切记此过程比较棘手和辣手
Note that this step can burn your hands...
# 对胃酸过敏的同学和手上有伤口的同学请谨慎操作
Again, if you are allergic to gastric acid or wounded, practice this step with care and caution
# 5分钟之后加入滚水清洗干净备用
After 5 minutes, add boiling water to clean the tripe and set it aside
# 下一步开始准备煮猪肚是辅料
Next step, prepare the aromatics for boiling the tripe
# 准备生姜1小块切成姜片备用
Slice up a small chunk of ginger
# 准备大葱1根切成片备用
Also slice some scallions, set aside
# 碗中加入适量 的高度白酒
Add some strong baijiu liquor into the bowl
# 下一步开始煮猪肚
Next, proceed to boiling the tripe
# 首先我们在锅中加入大半锅清水
Add a lot of water into the wok
# 然后将处理好的猪肚冷水下锅开大火煮开
Add the tripe into the cold water directly, and then boil over high heat
# 大火烧开之后再撇去浮末
Skim off the scums after it boils
# 将猪肚焯水定型之后捞出
Take the tripe out
# 然后将剩余的水倒入高压锅中备用
Transfer the boiled water to the pressure cooker
# 没有高压锅的同学可以直接煮40分钟
If you do not have a pressure cooker, boil the tripe for 40 minutes in a regular pot
# 下一步开始压猪肚
Next step: pressure cooking the tripe
# 将捞出的猪肚对半切开
Cut the tripe in half
# 然后将肚头上面的白色物质刮干净
Scrape off the white substances on the "head" of the tripe
# 这个部位非常腥臭必须去除干净
It is crucial to clean this place thoroughly to avoid bringing odor into the dish
# 处理干净之后放入高压锅里面上汽之后压8分钟
When done, put the tripe back to the pressure cooker to cook for another 8 minutes
# 同学们压制8分钟这个时长可以让猪肚口感爽脆不嫩不老
Remember that it takes 8 minutes to achieve the ideal crunchy texture for our dish that is neither too tender nor too chewy
# 喜欢有嚼劲的同学可以减少压制时间
If you prefer the tripe to be chewy, reduce the cooking time to your preference
# 8分钟之后即可捞出
After 8 minutes, take the tripe out
# 最后根据各自的实际需求将其切成块或者条装烹饪
Last step, cut the tripe into cubes or strips to fit the need of your desired dish
# 好了我的小技巧分享到此结束（完）
Alright, this is it for my techniques that I want to share with you